Finding Aid for Michigan Commission on Reform and Modernization of Government records, 1938-1939
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Commission on Reform and Modernization of Government records 1938-1939
Michigan. Commission on Reform and Modernization of Government.
1 linear foot (in 2 boxes)
851888 Ca.4b 2
Special commission appointed by Governor Frank Murphy and headed by Professor J. Ralston Hayden of University of Michigan. Correspondence, news releases and drafts of the report.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group came from the files of Professor J.R. Hayden.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Michigan Commission on Reform and Modernization of Government was established by Governor Frank Murphy in 1938. The commission was headed by University of Michigan political science professor J.R. Hayden.
The record group includes proceedings of the commission, final report to the governor with drafts and revisions, correspondence, clippings, press releases, and bill submitted to the legislature with the report
Subjects:
Hayden, Joseph Ralston, 1887-1945.; Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; Michigan--Politics and government--1939-1945.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
- Chairman's file (J.R. Hayden)
  - Index to the Commission Files (Box 1)
  - Proceedings of the Commission, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Financial Records (Box 1)
  - Originals of Documents in Bulletin 1 (Box 1)
  - Study Outline-November 19, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Drafts of Individual Sections-December 8, 1938, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Revised Drafts-December 8-10, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Suggested Revised Report-December 8-10, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Suggested Report December 19, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Suggested Report December 20, 1938, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Report as Revised by Commission-December 20, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Report submitted to Governor (Box 1)
  - Report as revised and printed (Box 2)
  - Bill submitted to legislature with the report (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Revisions (Box 2)
  - Master Copies of drafts, reports and letters, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Correspondence
    - July 1938 (Box 2)
    - August 1938 (Box 2)
    - September 1938 (Box 2)
    - October 1-13, 1938 (Box 2)
    - October 14-20, 1938 (Box 2)
    - October 20-30, 1938 (Box 2)
    - November 1-20, 1938 (Box 2)
    - November 21-26, 1938 (Box 2)
    - November 27-30, 1938 (Box 2)
    - December 1-10, 1938 (Box 2)
    - December 11-20, 1938 (Box 2)
    - December 21-31, 1938 (Box 2)
    - January 1-15, 1939 (Box 2)
    - January 16-31, 1939 (Box 2)
    - February-March 1939 (Box 2)
  - News Releases (Box 2)
  - News stories, 3 folders (Box 2)